Tanmaya Chaudhary

Data Scientist with around 2 years of experience in executing data-driven solution to increase efficiency and accuracy. Well-versed with Al solution development using Python, SQL and ML tools. More Focused on Machine Learning, MLOps and OCR problems. Enjoying data story telling with insights, and giving solutions for Data Science complex business problems.

tanmaychaudhary95@gmail.com

+91-9917033495

Uttar Pradesh, India

github.com/TanmayaChaudhary

:...

linkedin.com/in/tanmayachaudhary

in

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist

Ernst & Young LLP India 02/2022 – Present Work

Bangalore

Responsibilities in Capacity Prediction MLOps-End-To-End Pipeline

- Build modules of ML Prediction Models & Data Fetching from different platforms for consumption in pipeline.
- Build pipeline & Orchestrate using Azure Data Factory.
- Build CI/CD Pipeline using Github Actions.
- Report the output data into csv & saved into Azure Data Lake.
- Reproduce the Pipeline for different regions.

Responsibilities in Banking Customer Churn Prediction MLOps-End-To-End Pipeline

- Build web app using FastAPI for ML Model deployment.
- Containerized web app using Docker.
- Build CI/CD Pipeline using Github Actions.
- Deployed it using Azure Web App service.

Responsibilities in OCR Invoice Automation- End-To-End Pipeline

- Data gathering, Image pre-processing.
- Work on extraction of Invoice field details using Google Doc AI API.
- Report that extracted data into Excel/CSV files.
- Deployed it using Azure Web App.

Analyst

Work

KPMG Global Services India

04/2021 - 02/2022

Bangalore

• Assisting Oracle ERP Team in Oracle Business Unit

- Review the SQL reports.
- Review & create HCM Extract.
- Load data into Oracle Tables using HDL & HSDL Data Loaders.
- Data Modelling from Oracle Tables according to requirements.

Assisting Enterprise Access & Management Team in Cyber Security Business Unit

- Review the SQL reports.
- Review & create HCM Extract.
- Load data into Oracle Tables using HDL & HSDL Data Loaders.
- Data Modelling from Oracle Tables according to requirements.

Data Mining Intern

Peacock Solar Pvt. Ltd. Gurugram India

06/2021 - 08/2021

Work

WFH

• Responsibilities in Data Mining Team

- Analysed various data sources to discover fraud pattern & security breaches using Analytics Techniques, Data Matching, Duplicates & Gaps.
- Extract data from secondary sources & build datasets.
- Build dashboards & answer queries based on trends shown in dashboard.

Skills

Technical Skills: Python, Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, SQL, Keras, Google Doc Al.

Microsoft Azure ML Studio, Cognitive Services, Airflow, Docker, Flask. Data Bricks, Data Factory

Web Scrapping, Linear & Logistic Regression, Decision Tree, Random Forest, KNN and SVM.

Oracle OTBI & BIP, Sailpoint, Cherwell, Power BI, GitHub.

CETIFICATIONS

- Microsoft Azure Al Engineer Associate [Al-102, Score: 781/1000]
- Microsoft Azure Associate Data Scientist [DP-100, Score: 821/1000]
- Microsoft Azure Al Fundamentals [Al-900, Score: 933/1000]
- Oracle OCI Foundation 2021 Associate [1Z0-1085-21, Score: 82.7%]
- IBM Data Science Professional Certificate

EDUCATION

• Graduation B.Tech 2016-2020 (79.09%)

Institute of Engineering & Technology Alwar Rajasthan

 Higher Secondary 2014-2015 (72.8%)

Kendriya Vidyalaya No. 2 R.N Mathura U.P.

Secondary 2011-2013 (8.4 CGPA)
 Kendriya Vidyalaya No. 2 R.N Mathura
 U.P.

One Click CV

https://tanmayachaudhary.github.io/MyPort folio/

Personal Project - College Final Year Project 2019-2020

Smart Attendance System Using Face Recognition & Liveness Detection

Mark Attendance Using Face Recognition.

- No need to use ID card, Bio Metric or Pen Paper based attendance methods.
- Free from bypassing methods like paper or digital pic & video calling.